## Wahaj Ali

## FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

wahaj.ali96@yahoo.com | +92 307 5153811 | GitHub | LinkedIn | Wellfound | Twitter | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

Front-end web developer with a love to write clean code with accessible design. Expertise in HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript & React. Pair-programming and remote work enthusiast. Well-equipped to contribute to full-stack web development projects with a special focus on the front-end (UI) and deliver exceptional results. Loves to work quickly and efficiently.

## **SKILLS**

**Front-End:** JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3. **Back-End:** Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

**Test Driven Development**: RSpec, React testing library and Jest.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools, Slack.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Communication, Project Management,

Collaboration, Problem-solving.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

October 2022 - May 2023

<u>Homely</u>—A full-stack app that caters to individuals seeking to purchase residential properties & offers a user-friendly interface where users can register and conveniently schedule appointments to visit their selected houses of interest.

Built with: (React, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, and Redux). View the repository on GitHub.

TV Hub—The JavaScript project, TV show is a web app! With a user-friendly interface, you can easily search for and find all the information you need about any show. But that's not all! The web app also allows you to engage with your favorite shows in new and exciting ways.

• Built with: (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ES6). View the repository on GitHub.

<u>Metrics Web App</u>— The Metrics web app, 'Population Index', is a robust React-based Single Page Application (SPA) that harnesses the power of APIs to provide comprehensive and up-to-date population metrics for countries worldwide.! With an intuitive interface and powerful data visualization tools, you'll be able to quickly and easily access the latest population data for every country on the planet.

• Built with: (React, CSS, and JSX). View the repository on GitHub.

Every Penny— This project is created as part of the rails capstone at Microverse. This app is a mobile web application where a user manages his/her budget: have a list of transactions associated with a category, so that the user can see how much money is spent and on what. The user can add a new category or a new transaction inside a specific category. This app requires user authentication in order o start. It also requires user authorization to delete categories. CRUD operations are used to add, remove or update categories and transactions.

• Built with:(Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL). View the repository on GitHub.

INTERNATIONAL PAK ORTHOCON 2022— A basic HTML website for an event happening in my country. The website consisted of two pages: a Home page and an About page. The Home page provided information about the event, including the date, time, and location. It also included a banner image to grab the user's attention. The About page provided more information about the event, including the organizers, sponsors, and performers. It also included a brief history of the event and a photo gallery of past events. It uses media queries for a responsive design. It used JavaScript to add interactivity to the website, such as a dropdown menu for navigation.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript). <u>View the repository on GitHub.</u>

MICROVERSE Remote

#### Mentor (Volunteer)

December 2022 - February 2023

- Mentored 2 junior web developers, providing them with non-technical support via Zoom meetings and Slack conversations.
- Proposed improvements to their code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Helped them get familiar with code reviews and block & module repetition rules.
- Provided them advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

### **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE October 2022 – May 2023

## Remote Full-Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard GitFlow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

SSCIT September 2015 – August 2020

## **Electrical Computer Engineering, B.Sc**

- Main subjects: Programming in C, OOP and Data Structures, Embedded Systems, DBMS, and Network Security.
- Completed over ten semester projects, showcasing my skills in diverse areas, including the development of a line-following robot.
- Enhanced the ability to solve complex problems, and consistently delivered projects within defined deadlines through collaborative teamwork.
- Received an award and Certificate for 2nd Best Final Year Project. The project was a working prototype of smart glasses for Dyslexia patients. It was made using the Python language, and Raspberry Pi. It was a group project consisting of 4 members.